Guide to the Yale Events and Activities Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale events and activities photographs
1852-2003
RU 690
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
59.25
(135 boxes)
The materials consist of press photos taken by the Office of Public Affairs, formerly known as the News Bureau and the Office of Public Information to document events and activities at Yale.
Yale University. Office of Public Affairs
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 48-A (YRG 48-A), Yale pictorial records and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The photographs are arranged in four series: I. Photographs, 1852-1974. II. Photographs, 1950-circa 1994. III. Slides and transparencies, circa 1974-1989. IV. Oversize images, 1916, and subsequent accessions.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of press photos taken by the Office of Public Affairs, formerly known as the News Bureau and the Office of Public Information to document events and activities at Yale.
Photographs; Slides (photographs); Yale University -- Employees; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- History; Yale University -- Public relations; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Office of Public Affairs
- Photographs of events and activities, 1852-1974; Series I
  - Admissions
    - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alumni Conference, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Undergraduate, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Afro-American Studies, 1969, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni
    - Association of Yale Alumni
      - Association of Class Officers, Yale dinner (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Benedict, Ruth Landau and Davidson, Endicott P., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Chairman, Rose, Frederick P., Brewster, Kingman, Jr., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Committee on, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Founding Board of Governors, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Inauguration of New National Alumni Association, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Rose, Frederick P. and James Bates, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dowling, Brian, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hamilton, William, letter to President Kingman Brewster, Jr., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, Class of 1913, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Jones, T. A. Dwight, Class of 1908 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Lieberman, Joseph I., Class of 1967 Law, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Shellaby, Thatcher, Class of 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Wilmarth, Lewis S., hooked rug by Theodore Sizer, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Alumni Board
      - Banquet, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Banquet, Panel, "Law School and the Social Sciences", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Chairman, Pillsbury, Philip W., Shriver, R. Sargent, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Committee Executive, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - National Meeting
        - Dallas, Texas, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - Denver, Colorado, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - San Francisco, California, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - St. Louis, Missouri, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Panel, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Sturdy, Herbert F., '24, retirement, Williams, Frank O. H., '22s, election, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Commencement, first brother and sister B.A. recipients; First woman to graduate from Yale, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Convocation, 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 31 - 37)
    - Day, 1951-1969 (Box 2, Folder 38 - 56)
    - Day, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 57 - 61)
    - Dinners, general (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Divinity School Alumnus, Oldest living, Chapman, Harvey W. (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Fund
      - Anniversary, 75th, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 64)
      - Campaign Banquet, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 65 - 67)
      - Campaign Convocation, 1962- 1968 (Box 3, Folder 68 - 70)
      - Chairmen Meeting, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 71)
      - Election, Class agents, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 72)
      - Field, Curtis P., Gift, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 73)
      - New Haven Yale Club, Regional Committee, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - Staff, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - Travelers Insurance Company, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Graduates/Descendants, 1958-1974 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - House, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Magazine
      - Architecture photos, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 79)
      - Art New Guinea, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 80)
      - Campus shots, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 81)
      - "This Changing Campus", 1957-1965 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - Covers, 1941-1960 (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - Rugby, Lacrosse (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - "University in Action", 1951-1965 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - University functions (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - Yale Medical School, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 87)
      - Yale Orchestra, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 88)
      - Yale Personalities, 1955, undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Reunions
      - 1932 (Box 5, Folder 89A)
      - 1948-1959 (Box 5, Folder 90 - 101)
      - 1960-1966 (Box 6, Folder 102 - 108)
      - 1973 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Seminars, 1957-1966 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Taft, William Howard, 1918-1919, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Visits, King, Clarence H., Jr., Walker, G. Herbert III with Brewster, Kingman, Jr., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Yale Alumni Placement Service, National (Box 6, Folder 113)
  - American College Public Relations Association (ACPRA), 1957 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - American Studies Program, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Annexes (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Anniversary, 250th, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 117 - 118)
  - Anthropology, 1960-1968 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Applied Biodynamics, Alcohol Studies Center, 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Arms, University, 1949-1964 (Box 7, Folder 121)
  - Art Gallery
    - 1960-1965, undated (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - Alumni Art Shows, 1956- 1968 (Box 7, Folder 123 - 126)
    - Burke, James D., Curator of Prints and Drawings, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Collections and Exhibitions, A-D, 1952-1970 (Box 7, Folder 128 - 131)
    - Collections and Exhibitions, E-I, 1952-1970 (Box 8, Folder 132 - 133)
    - Concert, 17th Century English Music, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - Extension, 1951-1953 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - Garvan Silver Collection, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Graphic Arts, prints, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Mellon, Paul, Art Collection, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Restoration Department, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Sculpture Court, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 140 - 141)
    - Shestack, Alan, Director, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 142)
    - Trumbull, John, 1956-1961 (Box 9, Folder 143)
    - Visitors, 1968-1974 (Box 9, Folder 144)
    - Visual History Method, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 145)
  - Astronomy
    - Administration Building, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 146)
    - Argentina, Yale-Columbia Southern Observatory, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - Bethany, Connecticut, Observatory, 1957-1966 (Box 9, Folder 148)
    - Butler Telescope, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - Celestial Navigation, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 150)
    - Electronic Brain, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 151)
    - Greenland, Eclipse, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 152)
    - Library (Box 9, Folder 153)
    - Measuring machine, 1950-1952 (Box 9, Folder 154)
    - Moon (Box 9, Folder 155)
    - Radio Telescope, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 156)
    - Soviet Union, Brouwer, 1954-1959 (Box 9, Folder 157)
    - Staff, 1953-1960 (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Asxred Conference, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 159)
  - Athletic Association
    - Fisher Trophy Case, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 160)
    - Gales Ferry Boat House, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 161)
    - General, 1956-1972 (Box 9, Folder 162)
    - Morrissey, Anne, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 163)
    - Seabury, Robert B., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 164)
    - Sports, 1900-1951 (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Athletics, Cullman Courts, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 166)
  - Audio/Visual Center, 1954-1955 (Box 10, Folder 167)
  - Awards and Presentations
    - A-Bor, 1952-1968 (Box 10, Folder 168)
    - Brown, Gordon Memorial Prize, 1952-1972 (Box 10, Folder 169 - 170)
    - C-G, 1950-1968 (Box 10, Folder 171)
    - H-R, 1944-1972 (Box 11, Folder 172 - 174)
    - President Pusey Degree, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - S-X, 1950-1968 (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Secondary School Teachers, 1962-1967 (Box 11, Folder 177 - 178)
    - Secondary School Teachers, 1967-1970 (Box 12, Folder 179)
    - Y-Z, 1952-1961 (Box 12, Folder 180)
  - Baldwin, Abraham, grave, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 181)
  - Band, Yale, 1946-1953 (Box 12, Folder 182)
  - Banjo Club, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 183)
  - Basketball (Box 12, Folder 184)
  - Battell Chapel (Box 12, Folder 185)
  - Battell Chapel, 100th Anniversary - The Four Chaplains, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 186)
  - Beatles, The, rock group (Box 12, Folder 187)
  - Beach Boys, rock group (Box 12, Folder 188)
  - Becton Engineering and Science Center, 1965-1970 (Box 12, Folder 189)
  - Beinecke Library
    - 1960-1968 (Box 12, Folder 190 - 192)
    - Anniversary Celebration, 100th, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - Beinecke Brothers Portrait, 1966? (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - Christian manuscripts, rare papyrus of birth of Jesus, 1972 December 25 (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - Gospel manuscripts, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - Italian language, 500 year old book, first ever printed, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 197)
    - Osborn Collection, letters of King Charles II of England, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Osborn Collection, Purcell music, Henry Purcell, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 199)
  - Berdon Memorial Trees, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 200)
  - Biology
    - Galston, Arthur W., 1955-1971 (Box 13, Folder 201)
    - Harvey, E. Newton, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 202)
    - Kangaroos, Bettong of Australia, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 203)
    - Ruddle, Francis H., 1969 (Box 13, Folder 204)
  - Biophysics
    - Hartford Laboratory, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 205)
    - Molecular Biology, 1951, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 206)
  - Bladder Ball (Box 13, Folder 207)
  - Blue Jay Cleaners, brothers, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 208)
  - Bookstores (Box 13, Folder 209)
  - Boswell, James, 1971-1980 (Box 13, Folder 210)
  - Boyde, Malcolm, poster (Box 13, Folder 211)
  - Brandeis University (Box 13, Folder 212)
  - Brewster, Kingman, Jr., kidnapping, phony (Box 13, Folder 213)
  - British Art Center (Box 13, Folder 214)
    General
    See also: Yale Center for British Art, box 70, folder 1139.
  - BSAY, Black Student Alliance at Yale (Box 13, Folder 215)
  - Buildings, new, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 216)
  - Buildings, old, 1977, undated (Box 13, Folder 217)
  - Bureau of Highway Traffic
    - Esso Safety, Foundation Fellowship, 1954-1961 (Box 13, Folder 218)
    - Faculty and Student, 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 219)
    - Yale Institute for Traffic Training, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 220)
  - Bursary Program, 1950-1955 (Box 13, Folder 221 - 222)
  - Bursary Program, 1950-1955 (Box 14, Folder 223)
  - Butterfield's Band, rock group (Box 14, Folder 224)
  - Campus Police office (Box 14, Folder 225)
  - Carrillon (Box 14, Folder 226)
  - Cars, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 227)
  - Cemetery, Grove Street (Box 14, Folder 228)
  - Chapel Street (Box 14, Folder 229)
  - Chapels, 1948-1971 (Box 14, Folder 230)
  - Chemistry
    - Electronic Equipment, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 231)
    - Faculty, 1952-1972 (Box 14, Folder 232)
    - Gas-Flow Counter, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 233)
    - General Electric Conference (Box 14, Folder 234)
    - Kirkwood Medal, 1963-1971 (Box 14, Folder 235)
    - Lepoutre, Father Gerard, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 236)
    - Meites, Louis, in laboratory, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 237)
    - Onsager, Lars, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 238)
    - Oscilloscope, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 239)
    - Symposium, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 240)
    - Twin Calorimeter, 1949-1952 (Box 15, Folder 241)
    - Visitors, 1961-1963 (Box 15, Folder 242)
  - ChinaTrading Company (Box 15, Folder 243)
  - Choirs, Battell Chapel, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 244)
  - Christmas, downtown New Haven, Circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 245)
  - Church of Christ, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 246)
  - Civil Rights (Box 15, Folder 247)
  - Classics, 1965-1967 (Box 15, Folder 248)
  - Cleveland Orchestra and String Quartet (Box 15, Folder 249)
  - Clubs, 1948-1952 (Box 15, Folder 250)
  - Coalition for New University (Box 15, Folder 251)
  - Co-Education, 1969-1975 (Box 15, Folder 252)
  - Co-Education -- unidentified students, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 253)
  - Coin robbery, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 254)
  - College Bowl, General Electric Program (Box 15, Folder 255)
  - Colleges
    - Academic Trophy Cup, Gimbel Cup, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 256)
    - Berkeley, 1911-1968 (Box 16, Folder 257)
    - Branford, 1951-1964 (Box 16, Folder 258)
    - Calhoun, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 259)
    - Davenport, 1955-1964 (Box 16, Folder 260)
    - Timothy Dwight, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 261)
    - Jonathan Edwards, 1953-1964 (Box 16, Folder 262)
    - Masters, 1948, 1952-1959 (Box 16, Folder 263)
    - Morse and Stiles, 1959-1966 (Box 16, Folder 264)
    - Morse and Stiles, opening and dedication, 1962-1966 (Box 16, Folder 265)
    - Pierson, 1949-1971 (Box 16, Folder 266)
    - Proposed, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 267)
    - Saybrook, 1946-1963 (Box 17, Folder 268)
    - Silliman, 1951-1957 (Box 17, Folder 269)
    - Stiles (Box 17, Folder 270)
    - Trumbull, Drama (Box 17, Folder 271)
  - Columbus, Christopher (Box 17, Folder 272)
  - Commencement
    - 1932 (Box 17, Folder 272A)
    - 1946-1954 (Box 17, Folder 273 - 281)
    - 1955-1964 (Box 18, Folder 282 - 291)
    - 1965-1974 (Box 19, Folder 292 - 299)
    - pre 1975 (Box 19, Folder 300)
    - 1975 (Box 19, Folder 301)
    - 1976 (Box 19, Folder 302)
  - Commune, Hog Farm (Box 19, Folder 303)
  - Computer Center, 1960-1969 (Box 19, Folder 304)
  - Computer Science, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 305)
  - Conferences, 1951-1964 (Box 20, Folder 306)
  - Connecticut Mental Health Center, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 307)
  - Conservation, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 308)
  - Co-op, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 309)
  - CORE - Congress on Racial Equality (Box 20, Folder 310)
  - Corporation, The Yale, 1955-1965 (Box 20, Folder 311)
    See also:Yale Corporation,box 71, folder 1142.
  - Council Meeting, Yale, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 312)
  - Cozza, Carmen (Box 20, Folder 313)
  - Credit Bureau (Box 20, Folder 314)
  - Cross Campus "Happening" (Box 20, Folder 315)
  - "Crow" Editors (Box 20, Folder 316)
  - Crusade for Peace (Box 20, Folder 317)
  - Daily News, "Career", 1951 (Box 20, Folder 318)
    See also: Yale Daily News, box 71, folder 1144.
  - Daily News, Round the World Trip, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 319)
  - Daily News, "Seventy-Five", 1953 (Box 20, Folder 320)
  - Dance (Box 20, Folder 321)
  - Dances -- Proms, 1947-1949 (Box 20, Folder 322)
  - Deans, Freshman, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 323)
  - Debate, Yale-Harvard (Box 20, Folder 324)
  - DeForest Contest (Box 20, Folder 325)
  - Demonstrations
    - Cab, Youth fares (Box 20, Folder 326)
    - Cuban Blockade, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 327)
    - Peace, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 328)
  - Derby Day, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 329)
  - Development Board Meeting, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 330 - 331)
  - Dishwasher (Box 20, Folder 332)
  - Dominican Rally, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 333)
  - Draft Conference (Box 20, Folder 334)
  - Drama, 1965, undated (Box 20, Folder 335)
  - Dramat, 1965, undated (Box 20, Folder 336)
  - Drug Forum (Box 20, Folder 337)
  - Duke University (Box 20, Folder 338)
  - Economics, 1963-1970 (Box 20, Folder 339)
  - Economics, Cowles Foundation, 1956-1964 (Box 21, Folder 340)
  - Electrostatic Generator
    See: Van De Graaff Accelerator "Emperor", box 35, folders 597-598.
  - Emperor Accelerator, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 341 - 342)
  - Engineering, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 343)
  - Engineering and Applied Science, 1967-1973 (Box 21, Folder 344 - 345)
  - English, 1957-1970 (Box 21, Folder 346)
  - Equal Job Opportunity, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 347)
  - Excavations - Expeditions
    - Book of Isaiah, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 348)
    - Dead Sea Scrolls, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 349)
  - Excavations - Expeditions
    - Goetze and Bedoins, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 350)
    - Jericho Palace, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 351)
    - Jerusalem Burial Cave (Box 21, Folder 352)
    - Kingdom of Eshnunna, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 353)
    - Kingdom of Ugarit, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 354)
    - Logan Expedition to Yukon, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 355)
    - Madaba Expedition, Madaba -- Map of Palestine (Box 21, Folder 356)
    - Rosetta Stone, 1940-1943 (Box 21, Folder 357)
  - Exchange Students, 1952-1962 (Box 21, Folder 358)
  - The Exit, Cafe-Theater (Box 21, Folder 359)
  - Fellowships
    - 1959-1974 (Box 22, Folder 360)
    - McCormick, Robert, recipients, 1957-1963 (Box 22, Folder 361 - 362)
  - Fires (Box 22, Folder 363)
  - First National Bank of Boston (Box 22, Folder 364)
  - Fishing, Nova Scotia (Box 22, Folder 365)
  - Foreign Students
    - 1854 (Box 22, Folder 366)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 367 - 368)
    - 1952-1955 (Box 23, Folder 369 - 370)
    - 1963-1966 (Box 23, Folder 371)
  - Ford Foundation Students, 1952-1955 (Box 23, Folder 372)
  - Fraternities
    - Alpha Phi Omega, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 373)
    - Skull and Bones (Box 23, Folder 374)
  - Freedom Singers (Box 23, Folder 375)
  - French, Henry Peyre -- retirement, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 376)
  - Freshman year
    - 1948 (Box 23, Folder 377)
    - 1950 (Box 23, Folder 378)
    - 1951-1953 (Box 23, Folder 379)
    - 1954-1955, 1964, 1969, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 380)
  - Fugs, musical group (Box 24, Folder 381)
  - Funds, Botwinik, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 382)
  - Geology/Geophysics
    - Bateman, Alan M., 1971 (Box 24, Folder 383)
    - Ecology of Marine Animals, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 384)
    - Erosion, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 385)
    - Field trip, 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 386)
    - Fossils, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 387)
    - Mississippi samples, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 388)
    - "The Moon", 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 389)
    - Mud Mining, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 390)
    - Radiocarbon Laboratory, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 391)
    - Spectrograph, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 392)
    - Winchell Microscope (Box 24, Folder 393)
  - German Journalists (Box 24, Folder 394)
  - German Reading Room, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 395)
  - Girls, 1960s (Box 24, Folder 396)
  - Glee Club, 1865-1961 (Box 24, Folder 397)
  - God Squad (Box 24, Folder 398)
  - Grad Senate (Box 24, Folder 399)
  - Grove Street Cemetery, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 400)
  - Guru (Box 24, Folder 401)
  - Gymnastics (Box 24, Folder 402)
  - Hale, Nathan, 200th Birthday, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 403)
  - Halls
    - Commons Dining, 1948, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 404)
    - Connecticut, 1953-1968 (Box 25, Folder 405)
    - Dwight, 1931-1965 (Box 25, Folder 406)
    - Graduate Studies, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 407)
    - Helen Hadley, 1956-1962 (Box 25, Folder 408)
    - Vanderbilt, Old Campus (Box 25, Folder 409)
    - Weir (Box 25, Folder 410)
    - Wrexham (Box 25, Folder 411)
    - Woolsey, 1966-1970 (Box 25, Folder 412)
  - Hammond Laboratory, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 413)
  - HarknessTower (Box 25, Folder 414)
  - Harlem, New York City, 1919 (Box 25, Folder 415)
  - Hartford, John, Laboratory of Yale University (Box 25, Folder 416)
  - Harvard weekend, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 417)
  - Health Department, 1955-1972 (Box 25, Folder 418)
  - Heelers Competitions (Box 25, Folder 419)
  - Hill Arts (Box 25, Folder 420)
  - Hillel Foundation, 1949-1972 (Box 25, Folder 421)
  - Hillhouse High School (Box 25, Folder 422)
  - Hillhouse Restaurant (Box 25, Folder 423)
  - Historical, 1965-1968 (Box 25, Folder 424)
  - History Department, 1961-1964 (Box 25, Folder 425)
  - History of Art, Vincent J. Scully, Jr., 1970 (Box 25, Folder 426)
  - History of Science and Medicine, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 427)
  - Hoaxes (Box 25, Folder 428)
  - Hockey, George Semler (Box 25, Folder 429)
  - Hofbrau House Revue (Box 26, Folder 430)
  - Hometown Releases, Freshman, 1953-1965
    - States, A-Q (Box 26, Folder 431 - 435)
    - States, R-Z (Box 27, Folder 436)
  - Housing, 1953-1962 (Box 27, Folder 437)
  - Howard University Choir (Box 27, Folder 438)
  - Human Relations Area Files, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 439)
  - Hungry Charlie's, restaurant (Box 27, Folder 440)
  - Hypnotism, Weber, W. (Box 27, Folder 441)
  - Industrial Administration, 1950-1965 (Box 27, Folder 442)
  - Ingalls, David S., Rink, 1956-1967 (Box 27, Folder 443 - 444)
  - Inside-Out Panel (Box 27, Folder 445)
  - Institute of Far Eastern Languages, 1958-1962 (Box 27, Folder 446)
  - Institute of Human Relations, 1948-1951 (Box 27, Folder 447)
  - International Student Center (Box 27, Folder 448)
  - Ivy League, Crests of (Box 27, Folder 449)
  - Japanese Studies, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 450)
  - Kennedy International Airport, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 451)
  - The Kinsmen (Box 28, Folder 452)
  - Kline
    - Biology (Box 28, Folder 453 - 454)
    - Botany -- Chloromycetin, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 455)
    - Botany -- Herbarium, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 456)
    - Botany, Plant Physiology, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 457)
    - Botany, "Sex Life of the Bacteria", 1947-1952 (Box 28, Folder 458 - 459)
    - Chemistry, 1964-1965 (Box 28, Folder 460)
    - Geology, 1961-1969 (Box 28, Folder 461 - 462)
    - Geology, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 463)
    - Power Plant, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 464)
    - Science Center, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 465)
  - Kosher Kitchen (Box 29, Folder 466)
  - Labor-Management Center, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 467)
  - Laboratories
    - Bingham Oceanographic, 1953-1957 (Box 29, Folder 468 - 469)
    - Dunham (Box 29, Folder 470)
    - Edwards Street, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 471)
    - Epidemiology and Public Health (Box 29, Folder 472)
    - Geochronometric, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 473)
    - Gibbs, Josiah Willard
      - 1952-1961 (Box 29, Folder 474 - 475)
    - Visit of Lee DeForest, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 476)
    - Metallurgy, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 477)
    - Oceanographic and Ornithological, 1959-1966 (Box 30, Folder 478)
  - Lampoon Building and Councilman Vallucci (Box 30, Folder 479)
  - Language Center, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 480)
  - Language Institute for Far Eastern Language, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 481)
  - Latin American Students (Box 30, Folder 482)
  - "Laughing Gas" (Box 30, Folder 483)
  - Laundry, Yale Student, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 484)
  - Liggetts, Quality Cutlers (Box 31, Folder 493)
  - Light Show (Box 31, Folder 494)
  - Lincoln Theater (Box 31, Folder 495)
  - Lindsay headquarters, election night, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 496)
  - Linguistics Dictionary
    - Burmese, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 497)
    - Korean, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 498)
  - Literary Magazine, Yale, 1919, undated (Box 31, Folder 499)
  - Lloyd Quartet, Charles (Box 31, Folder 500)
  - Long Wharf Theater (Box 31, Folder 501)
  - Louis Award, Yale Film Society (Box 31, Folder 502)
  - McKayle Dance Company (Box 31, Folder 503)
  - Macy's (Box 31, Folder 504)
  - Malkin's Bar (Box 31, Folder 505)
  - Map of Yale, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 506)
  - Marine Corp Band (Box 31, Folder 507)
  - Machu Picchu, tomb (Box 31, Folder 508)
  - Maxie's, 1966-1967 (Box 31, Folder 509)
  - May Day, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 510)
  - Memorial tablets, 1950-1959 (Box 31, Folder 511)
  - Meridith, James, riots, University of Mississippi, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 512)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentified (Box 32, Folder 513)
  - Mississippi University, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 514)
  - The Moderator, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 515)
  - Monuments, Claes Oldenburg's "Lipstick", 1969 (Box 32, Folder 516)
  - Mory's, staff, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 517)
  - Moscow Theater (Box 32, Folder 518)
  - Music (Box 32, Folder 519)
  - Musical Instrument Collection, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 520)
  - Muslims, Black (Box 32, Folder 521)
  - Narcotics Hearings (Box 32, Folder 522)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 523)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) -- cartoon (Box 32, Folder 524)
  - Navy game, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 525)
  - Navy Recruiting Officers Training Center (NROTC) (Box 32, Folder 526)